

≥ veeracse64@gmail.com

+91-8807321928

Salem, India

in http://linkedin.com/in/veerichetty-ravi

SUMMARY

A highly motivated and passionate engineer who has **7+ years of work experience** to work in a creative and challenging environment that encourages learning and creativity, provides exposure to new heights and stimulates professional growth.

SKILLS

- Very good experience with **PHP** programming language and **Yii**, **Laravel** frameworks.
- Good knowledge in JavaScript, Python and jQuery.
- Good knowledge in relational databases specializing in MySQL.
- Good experience with REST API, Chatbot.
- Good knowledge in **Git** version control system.
- Familiarity with **Docker** and **RabbitMQ**.
- Familiarity with Java, Angular, Vue.js.

EXPERIENCE

Staff Consultant

Oracle Solution Services India May 2021 - Present

OAP is a custom online interface tool for BRM. Oracle Communications Billing and Revenue Management (BRM) provides an end-to-end revenue management system for communications service providers. Use BRM to configure product offerings, create customer accounts, charge for service usage, collect and analyze revenue, and manage customer relationships.

Responsibilities

Analyzing the requirement given by the Team lead. Designing the application based on the requirement. Writing efficient code for the product. Review and debug code.

Senior Software Engineer

TNQ Technologies Jan 2020 - May 2021

Proof Central is an online interface tool you can quickly and easily apply corrections, comments and change requests in your proof and submit them directly for correction. The Proof Central author proofing solution allows you to Review and answer queries from the copy editor, Insert text directly into the article, Apply styling for, bold, italic, superscript and subscript text, Add attachments to replace or add to your submission, Add remarks to your attachments to describe them or direct us on how they are to be used, Apply edits and corrections to table cells and the table formatting, Annotate graphics with precision edits and comments, Edit math in the math editor mode or in the LaTex version mode of the equation, Delete content in the text, graphics or equations, Invite one or more co-authors to the proof to provide corrections, Output a report of your edits and instructions you have made in your article, Review your article in the journal style, including the associated reference style, Add, edit or remove references, reference citations or other citations, using a PDF generator, or to switch to PDF annotation mode.

Responsibilities

Analyzing the requirement given by the Product Owner. Designing the product based on the requirement. Writing efficient code for the product. Review and debug code. Automate the deployment process.

Junior Software Engineer

Anubavam Technologies Dec 2015 - Dec 2019

Creatrix Campus (ERP) provides a comprehensive cloud-based solution for schools and institutions of higher learning. The robust structure includes a parent communication system, student information system, and content management system. The entire campus community can benefit from global notifications, advanced reporting features and mobile applications.

Responsibilities

Designing and developing modules such as Report Builder, Workflow management, Data Importer and Exporter, Chabot. Developing the REST API and exposed for Mobile application and third parties. Getting feedback from client and incorporating suggested changes in modules.

Junior Software Engineer

Innovace Technology Solution Jun 2014 - Dec 2015

Secured Mail Server & Email Application is a secured mailing system. It has unique encryption and decryption techniques and also unique SSL and IPSec components are integrated so that transmission will much secured. Usual mails management, flash messages, contact management, task management, profile management, calendar management are the components of this project. While sending mail to outside mailing system (such as Gmail, yahoo etc.,) mail data will be encrypted and send as encrypted attachment. Encrypted attachment will be decrypted only with secure container.

Responsibilities

User Interface and Backend Development for Admin Panel. Write, Review and debug code.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

M.A.M College of Engineering and Technology Jun 2010 - Apr 2014

Studied Computer Science and Engineering.

LANGUAGES

Tamil - Native English - Fluent